Guide to the Loeb Family Papers, 1834-1995 MS 914
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Loeb Family Papers
1834-1995
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Proler, Freda "Bitsy"; Rosenthal, Julien
MS 914
2.5 Linear Feet 2 boxes
This collection consists of two boxes containing Emanuel (Beaumont) programs, news clippings, photographs, certificates, a remembrance card, marriage contract (Ketubah), and legal documents, such as deeds and wills, ranging from 1834 to 1995.
Biographical / Historical
Delphine Regensberger was born 19 October 1846, in New Orleans, Louisiana, to Lasen and Pauline (Frank) Regensberger.
Moise (Michel) Hirsh was born in France in 1843. Hirsch and Regensberger met and married in New Orleans. The couple had three children, Louis, Julia, and Mildred before Michel Hirsh died in 1868.
Morris (Moses) Loeb was born in Germany in 1870. He married Delphine Regensberger Hirsch in 1870. The two settled in Beaumont, Texas, and had two children, Martha and Joseph.
Delphine Loeb died 17 October 1912 and Morris Loeb died in 1908.
Content Description
Two boxes consisting of Emanuel (Beaumont) programs, news clippings, photographs, certificates, a remembrance card, marriage contract (Ketubah), and legal documents, such as deeds and wills, document the lives of members of the Loeb family from 1834 to 1995. The family was a part of the late 19th and early 20th centuries Jewish communities in Beaumont, Texas, and New Orleans, Louisiana. These documents show their involvement in real estate, synagogue life, travel, and more.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials open for research.
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center and requires 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Freda "Bitsy" Proler and Julien Rosenthal, June 2019.
Arrangement
The materials in this collection have been arranged in two series as follows:
Series I: General; Series II: Photographs
Index Terms
Subjects
Jews and Jewish life
Document Types
legal documents; photographs
Subjects (Persons)
Proler, Freda "Bitsy"; Rosenthal, Julien
- Series I: General
  - Bliss Abstract of Title, 1834-1929 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ketubah, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Property Documents, 1882-1927 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Funeral Card, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Grandma Loeb's European Diary, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Delphine Loeb Will, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bill of Cost, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bohrer Abstract of Title, 1913-1937 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Red Cross Certificate, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Poem For Julia Bohrer, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Ladies' Benevolent Society Pamphlet, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Temple Emanuel Informational Booklet, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Testimonial of Appreciation, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - News Clippings, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Series II: Photographs
  - Family Photographs (1 of 3), 1886-1927 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Family Photographs (2 of 3), 1890-1918 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Family Photographs (3 of 3), 1905-1945 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Portrait of M. J. Loeb, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Portrait of Delphine Loeb, n.d. (Box 2)